onlinesociety.org 2003-04-08

# Online Society Privacy Policy

|  |  |  |  |   
---|---|---|---|---  
| **About Us** |   
|  | • | Company Overview |   
|  | • | Contact Us |   
|  | • | Employment |   
|  | • | In The News |   
|  | • | Press Releases |   
   
| **Products and Services** |   
|  | • | Products and Services Overview |   
|  | • | coPortal Structure |   
|  | • | Country Identifier |   
|  | • | FAQs |   
|  | • | Regional Theme Sites |   
|  | • | Site Map |   
   
| **Agreements & Policies** |   
|  | • | **Privacy Policy** |   
|  | • |  Terms Of Use Agreement |   
|  | • | Suggest A Site Agreement |   
   
| **Advertising** |   
|  | • | Banners & Sponsored Links |   
|  | • | coPortal Membership  |   
|  |  |  |   
|  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |   
---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---  
| **Online Society's Commitment to Privacy** |   
| Online Society Inc., the sole owner of OnlineSociety.com and its associated community of Regional Theme Sites ("Sites"), has assembled this Privacy Policy ("Policy") to articulate how we value, collect, utilize, and protect the information we gather. Foremost is our assurance to you that security and your privacy will be treated and maintained in the highest regard, and that our actions will not differ from what is documented in this Policy. It is our belief that obtaining your approval, acceptance, trust, and peace of mind on how we treat your privacy and security is perhaps the greatest and most fundamental asset that we must earn in order for us to build a continuing relationship. |   
| The Policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect, use and safeguard the personal information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our Sites, products, and services. This statement as well as our practices will be continuously assessed and benchmarked against new technologies, business practices and our customers' needs. |   
| **What Information Do We Collect?** |   
| When you visit our Sites you may provide us with two types of information:  |   
| • |  | Personal information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected on an individual basis. |   
| • |  | Web site use information collected on an aggregate basis as you and others browse our Sites. |   
| **1.** |  | **Personal Information You Choose to Provide** |   
| **Membership Information** |   
| If you choose to become a member, you will need to provide personal information about yourself. For example, you may need to provide the following information: |   
| • |  | First name |   
| • |  | Last name (surname) |   
| • |  | City |   
| • |  | State/Province |   
| • |  | Zip/Postal Code |   
| • |  | Country |   
| • |  | Birth Date |   
| • |  | Email address |   
| • |  | Gender |   
| Additionally, it is optional for the prospective Member to provide other Demographic information (such as your occupation, the Industry that's associated with your Occupation, your Regional preferences, as well as the Themes that maintain your interest), but it is encouraged so that we may personalize your experience and deliver Sites and services consistent with our Member's interests. |   
| **Information from Children** |   
| Online Society does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children. Further, the service that we offer (for which membership and personal information is required) does not lend itself to children under 13-years of age. |   
| **Email Information** |   
| If you choose to correspond with us through email, we may retain the contents of your email messages together with your email address and our responses. We provide the same protections for these electronic communications that we employ in the maintenance of information received by mail and telephone. |   
| Online Society also offers two convenience features that allow you to either send a news article to another individual or allows you to recommend Online Society to a friend. In either situation you are asked to provide your email address as well as the email addresses of everyone you wish to address in your communication. None of the email addresses that are included in either of these convenience features (as well as any text message that you might supply) are retained by us. |   
| **Credit Card Information** |   
| In order to obtain some of our services, you will need to send us payment. Currently Online Society has chosen to utilize a payment system that relies on Credit Cards. You can rest assured that we do not retain your Credit Card number, at any time, for any purpose.  |   
| **2.** |  | **Web Site Use Information** |   
| Similar to other commercial Web sites, our Sites utilize a standard technology called "cookies" (see explanation below, "What Are Cookies?") and Web server logs to collect information about how our Sites are used. Information gathered through cookies and Web server logs may include the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at our Sites, and the Web sites visited just before and just after our Sites. This information is collected on an aggregate basis. None of this information is associated with you as an individual. |   
| **How Do We Use the Personal Information That You Provide to Us?** |   
| Broadly speaking, we use personal information for purposes of administering our business activities, formulating strategic business decisions, providing customer service, and making available other products and services to our customers and prospective customers. Occasionally, we may also use the information we collect to notify you about important changes to our Sites, new services and special offers we think you will find valuable. The lists used to send you product and service offers are developed and managed under our traditional corporate standards designed to safeguard the security and privacy of our customers' personal information.  |   
| **What Are Cookies?** |   
| Cookies are a feature of Web browser software that allows Web servers to recognize the computer used to access a Web site. Cookies are small pieces of data that are stored by a user's Web browser on the user's hard drive. Cookies can remember what information a user accesses on one Web page to simplify subsequent interactions with that Web site by the same user or to use the information to streamline the user's transactions on related Web pages. This makes it easier for a user to move from Web page to Web page and to complete commercial transactions over the Internet. Cookies should make your online experience easier and more personalized.  |   
| **How Do We Use Information We Collect from Cookies?** |   
| We use Web site browser software tools such as cookies and Web server logs to gather information about our Sites users' browsing activities, in order to constantly improve our Sites and better serve our customers. This information assists us to design and arrange our Web pages in the most user friendly manner and to continually improve our Sites to better meet the needs of our current and prospective customers. Cookies help us collect important business and technical statistics. The information in the cookies lets us trace the paths followed by users to our Sites as they move from one page to another. Web server logs allow us to count how many people visit our Sites and evaluate our Site's visitor capacity. We do not use these technologies to capture your individual email address or any personally identifying information about you, although they do permit us to send focused online banner advertisements or other such responses to you. |   
| **Messages concerning Online Society, and Announcements from coPortal Members** |   
| If you are a Member, we may occasionally send you an email newsletter providing information concerning Online Society that we believe you will find useful, such as: |   
| • |  | Important changes to our Sites. |   
| • |  | New Online Society services and special offers we think you will find valuable. |   
| • |  | Announcements on new coPortal Members. |   
| • |  | Announcements on newly introduced Themes |   
| Further, if you are a Member, we may occasionally send you messages through our system that was initiated by our coPortal Members for your attention, such as: |   
| • |  | Informing you of a new marketing incentive that is available from a specific coPortal Member. |   
| • |  | Sending you a news announcement concerning a coPortal Member's new product or service. |   
| • |  | Advising you of a news bulletin that affects a particular coPortal Member. |   
| • |  | Providing you a special promotional offer from a specific coPortal Member. |   
| It is our policy to only send such messages to those Members who have previously provided us permission to do so. If you do not wish to continue receiving such emails, you may go to your Member Profile and uncheck the applicable boxes that give us your permission to send such messages. |   
| **How Do We Secure Information Transmissions?** |   
| When you send credit card information to Online Society, a secure server software which we have licensed encrypts all information you input before it is sent to us. The information is scrambled en route and decoded once it reaches Online Society, using industry standard 128-bit SSL encryption to protect the data transmission. |   
| **How do I Know I am on a Secured Site** |   
| You can view our Digital Certificate that is issued from VeriSign by double clicking on the closed lock image on the bottom bar of your browser. This Certificate will show that you are sending your personal information to Online Society. |   
| **3.** |  | **Data Security, Accessibility, and Disclosure** |   
| **Information Security** |   
| We utilize current Computer, Network and Internet security methods and techniques to maintain the security of your personally identifiable information, such that it is confined to a database that is apart from a live server, and also protected by a firewall. Your Online Society Account information is password protected, requiring a minimum of eight characters to provide additional protection for your personal information. Furthermore, when you conduct a monetary transaction we do not store or maintain your Credit Card number that you provide to process such transactions. |   
| However, in spite of all of our efforts to safeguard your privacy, neither Online Society nor any other system can provide you a 100% guarantee concerning the security of your personal information. When we do receive your personal information we treat it with the highest regard, and use all reasonable efforts and measures to safeguard its security on our systems. |   
| **Employee Access** |   
| Our corporate values, ethical standards, policies and practices are committed to the protection of our customer's information. Consequently, our business practices: |   
| • |  | Limit the number of employees who have accessibility to confidential information. |   
| • |  | Limit the use and disclosure of specific information to only authorized individuals having a need for such information to perform a specific function. |   
| • |  | Require an authorized password to access such information. |   
| **How Can You Access, Update, or Delete Your Membership Information?** |   
|  You may access and update your personally identifiable membership information that we maintain in our database, by accessing your Profile Info within the Member Account Center. We encourage you to use this feature as often as needed to update and keep your entire account current. From here, you can: |   
| • |  | Periodically change your Member Password |   
| • |  | Update or change your "Secret Question", which is utilized in the event you forget your password. |   
| • |  | Update your personal account information, including your email address. |   
| • |  | Activate or deactivate: |   
| • |  | Your preference towards certain Themes. Any new Themes that have been added subsequent to becoming a Member will also be available for your activation at this time, if you so wish. |   
| • |  | Your capability to receive periodic announcements and emails from Online Society. |   
| • |  | The feature that will allow you to receive communications from our coPortal Members that are aligned with your interest to specific Themes. |   
| Online Society does not have a method currently that allows you to completely delete a Member's information from our database. |   
| **Do We Sell or Disclose any of your Information to Outside Parties?** |   
| Online Society does not share, rent, or sell any personally identifiable data about you. The only type of information that we might provide is aggregated data about our users and Members, Web site traffic patterns, and related Web site information. Such aggregated data could be made available to our coPortal Members, affiliates, or reputable third parties. However this information will not include any personally identifiable data that's specific to any one individual. |   
| In the event you opt to receive email messages from our coPortal members (when you elect to do so within the "Sign Up to Become a Member" form), you will receive such email messages through Online Society (acting as an intermediary) rather than directly from the coPortal Member. We do this as an extra precautionary step and courtesy to avoid disclosing your email address to any third party. When we send such communications to you we will also indicate the particular coPortal Member who has requested us to send the email, as well as their email address so that you may respond to them directly. If you choose to respond to a coPortal member directly through this venue, you should be aware that your email address will be seen and known by the coPortal Member. |   
| **What About Legally Compelled Disclosure of Information?** |   
| We may disclose personal information when legally compelled to do so, in other words, when we, in good faith, believe that the law requires it, or for the protection of our legal rights. |   
| **4.** |  | **Other Web Site Links** |   
| **What About Other Web Site Links?** |   
| We are not responsible for the practices employed by Web sites linked to or from our Sites nor the information or content contained therein. Such links found on our Sites are meant as a convenience for our users, and does not constitute any kind of endorsement. Often links to other Web sites are provided solely as pointers to information on topics that may be useful to the users of our Sites. |   
| Please remember that when you use a link to go from our Web site to another Web site, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other Web site, including Web sites that have a link on our Sites, is subject to that Web site's own rules and policies. Please read over their rules and policies before proceeding. |   
| **5.** |  | **Your Consent and Future Policy Changes** |   
| **Your Consent and Future Changes to our Policy** |   
| By using our Sites you consent to our collection and use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on our Web site to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it, protect it, and under what circumstances we may disclose it. |
